



lam Mischke





Summary

Strong work ethic Full-stack Engineer that learns quickly and is a committed team player. 4-years of startup experience working in an agile and TDD environment. Served in the United States Navy as a Network Administrator.

Problem Solving Time Management Organization Strong Communication Skills

Proficient in:

Python Git Swift Linux/Bash Docker C, C++ Django/SQL

Working knowledge of:

Network Adminstration Web Development Blockchain A.I. & Neural Networks Electrical Engineering Excel & Word Processors Terraform

Experience

FunFunFun Inc.

May 2020-June 2022

Full-stack Software Engineer

- Built a Django and GraphQL backend to facilitate over 10,000 users, with CI/CD tools using GitHub actions.
- · Created a series of Firebase, Firestore, and Google Storage triggers to create a video processing pipeline that asynchronously cut over 8,000 videos.
- Deployed a fully SwiftUI iOS app from the ground up with automatic deployment tools to deploy directly to the App Store.
- Created a fully testable local Docker environment including all tools needed for development.

Coinmine

May 2018- April 2020

Software Engineer

- · Built and maintained mineOS, an Arch Linux-Based distro, and fabricated build and deployment tools for distributing OS images through a test and build pipeline for over 3000 edge compute devices.
- Used Agile, Extreme Programming and Test Driven Development methodologies to deploy, update, and configure a Django based backend with over 8,000 users.
- · Arranged and operated analytical, deployment, and pipeline tools such as: CircleCI, Code Climate, Datadog, and Sentry.
- Worked with overseas distribution centers to construct and create Standard Operating Procedures (SOP) for assembly and manufacturing.

Caterpillar Financial Services Corporation

May 2017 – July 2017

Information Services Intern-Network Team

- Led research, meetings, and recommended the replacement of a network team application. Worked as liaison between team members and company solutions.
- Sought out quote to be implemented into the yearly budget.
- Researched and developed a web dashboard that displayed global network information with Python and Flask using a SQL database. Used JavaScript, J-Query, Bootstrap, AJAX, and Google Charts to form a coherent and simple-to-use website. Implemented a search function that integrated with database calls to speed up information flow.

United States Navy

July 2008 - July 2014

Computer and Network Technician

- Held a Secret Clearance and handled the Electronic Key Management System.
- Upkeep and corrective maintenance of the Ship's Self Defense System, Open architecture network server and computer systems, Battle Force Tactical Trainer network, and Cooperative Engagement Capability LAN.
- Efficiently led as work center supervisor, 8 personnel in accomplishing over 1,634 maintenance actions with a 94% maintenance accomplishment rate, managing 372 maintenance checks and repairs.

Education

Middle Tennessee State University - 3.67 GPA

2014 - 2018

Bachelor of Science (B.S.), Computer Science

- Minor in Mathematics
- Dean's List 2014-2018
- Member of Association of Computing Machinery (ACM)
- Member of the Upsilon Pi Epsilon Computer Honor Society

Interests

Arch Linux, cryptocurrency, hiking, snowboarding, music, lifting weights, running, and learning new programming things.